## MONICA CHOPRAFeatured Resume

Foreign English Teacher seeking roles in Students Management, Curriculum Development, Coaching, Academic Research, School Development, Counselling, Training, Development, Records Management, Personality Development, Administration Management, Quality Control

Current Designation: Foreign English Teacher

Current Company: Shijiazhuang foreign language Education Group

Current Location: Shijiazhuang, China

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, China, Singapore

Functional Area: Teaching / Education

Role: Class Teacher / Classroom coordinator

Industry: Education/Teaching/Training

Total Experience: 29 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Sc [Physics, Math, Electronics]

Key Skills: Foreign English Teacher, Class Teacher / Classroom Coordinator, Students
Management, Curriculum Development, Coaching, Academic Research, School
Development, Counselling, Training, Records Management, Personality Development, Administration
Management

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: f39a1ef806cc44c393fbee6ab1e5f826Last Active: 17-Sep-20Last Modified: 17-Sep-20

Jump to SectionWork Experience | Education |

Summary

An esteemed Academician offering nearly 29 years of impeccable career in

working with Group of Institutions & International Schools across India and China key focus on achieving student's growth objectives through teaching & mentoring, curriculum development, training & development and student's management Presently working as Foreign English Teacher in China with one of the leading International Group; acted as a Volunteer for Beijing Olympics & Para Olympics Known internationally for groundbreaking efforts in curriculum & teaching planning with excellence in quickly sizing up the assignments, setting priorities, creating a timeline, delivering lectures of high quality content for students within defined timeframes and evaluating students' performance as per child-led activities and project based learnings

Work Experience

Shijiazhuang foreign language Education Group as Foreign English Teacher Sep 2019 to Till Date

Role:

Showcasing excellence in designing & following teaching plans; teaching alphabets and numeracy along with personal, social and emotional skills

Proven capabilities in organizing learning material and resources

Leveraging skills in implementing multiple innovative & instructional methods (stories, media, structured games, art, outdoor activities etc.) to motivate & stimulate children?s abilities

Assessing children?s performance and progress to ensure they are mastering the skills on regular basis

Following and adhering to the defined teaching standards and safety regulations

Yew Wah International Educational Kindergarten as ECE Teacher Sep 2016 to Jul 2019

Role:

Worked in close coordination with:

o English Teacher for preparation of monthly plans

o Chinese Co-Teacher for preparation of daily plans

Developed course materials for students to complete in the classroom

Evaluated students' performances as per child-led activities & project based learnings

Maintained an open line of communication with parents/guardians & provided

appropriate information

Entrusted with the responsibility of planning the class activities for festivals, open days and sports day

Jan'15 - Jan'16: Yew Chung International School of Beijing as English Teacher (Cover for Teacher on Maternity Leave)

Role:

Concocted & delivered lectures to Secondary & Lower Secondary students on English, Mathematics, Science and Social Studies students

Evaluated and prepared the report cards for the students

Evaluated the students individually to identify areas of difficulty

BIBA International School as ECE Teacher

Aug 2013 to Jan 2015

Role:

Acted as a core member of the team & developed curriculum, provided modifications and developed methods of evaluation

Implemented innovative teaching methods (such as lectures, discussions and demonstrations) to ensure students reach their full potential and to retain student interest and maximize learning

Fostered the success of students by facilitating the development, communication, implementation & evaluation of a shared vision of learning that reflects excellence Exhibited excellence in identifying the early signs of emotional, developmental & health problems in students and followed with parents for the same Ensured discipline by observing students' work, behavior & attendance Responded to all classroom queries in a spontaneous manner to foster a healthy learning atmosphere in class

Interacted and communicated with students, parents and the community to build an environment that maximizes student learning, academic performance & social growth Encouraged students to persevere with challenging tasks

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Physics, Math, Electronics) from Nagpur University in 1991

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma in Early Childhood Care and Education